comcastbusiness.net 2017-10-03

# Privacy Statement

**

## Comcast Business Services Privacy Notice

**

For Comcast Business Internet, Phone, TV, and Ethernet

Summary of this privacy notice  
This privacy notice applies to Comcast Business Internet, phone, TV, and Ethernet services.  It describes the limitations imposed on our collection and disclosure of personally identifiable information about subscribers, the nature of personally identifiable information we collect, how we use that information, when and why we may disclose that information and to whom, how long we maintain that information, how subscribers can access their personally identifiable information, how subscribers can set preferences and opt out of certain uses of information, and subscribers’ rights under law and this notice concerning their personally identifiable information.  Please read the entire notice to understand our privacy policies and practices.

Why is Comcast providing this notice?  
As a subscriber to cable service or other services provided by Comcast, you are entitled under Section 631 of the federal Cable Communications Policy Act of 1984, as amended, (the “Cable Act”) to know the following: 

  * the limitations imposed by the Cable Act upon cable operators in the collection and disclosure of personally identifiable information about subscribers; 
  * the nature of personally identifiable information we collect; 
  * the nature of the use of personally identifiable information; 
  * under what conditions and circumstances we may disclose personally identifiable information and to whom; 
  * the period during which we maintain personally identifiable information; 
  * the times and places at which you may have access to your personally identifiable information; and 
  * your rights under the Cable Act concerning personally identifiable information and its collection and disclosure. 

Personally identifiable information is information that identifies a particular person; it does not include de-identified, anonymous, or aggregate data that does not identify a particular person or persons.  This notice is also provided to you in accordance with applicable California law, which only applies to our customers located in California who are served by a cable television corporation.

In addition, Section 222 of the Communications Act of 1934, as amended, (the “Communications Act”) provides additional privacy protections for certain information related to our phone and retail Internet services:

  * information about the quantity, technical configuration, type, destination, location, and amount of your use of the phone and retail Internet services; and
  * information contained on your bill concerning the type of phone services and features you receive.

That information is known as customer proprietary network information or CPNI for short. This notice, which includes our CPNI Policy, describes what CPNI we obtain, how we protect it, and how it may be used. If you are a customer of our phone and retail Internet services, you have the right, and Comcast has a duty, under the Communications Act and applicable state law, to protect the confidentiality of CPNI.   In addition, the FCC’s rules provide additional privacy protections specific to our phone services that we describe in this notice.

We explain below under “How do I give or withhold my approval for Comcast to use CPNI to market additional products and services to me?” how you can approve our use of CPNI or withdraw your approval if Comcast decides to use CPNI for marketing purposes.

 **Special Note:** Our CPNI Policy applies to the phone and retail Internet communications-related services provided by the applicable Comcast operating company that delivers those services to our customers.

In this notice, the terms “Comcast,” “we,” “us,” or “our” refer to the operating company subsidiary or subsidiaries or affiliates of Comcast Cable Communications, LLC that (i) owns and/or operates the cable television system in your area pursuant to a cable television franchise with the local franchising authority, or (ii) is the operating company that delivers phone services in your area.  The term “you,” “customer,” and “subscriber” refers to the commercial customer subscribing to one or more of our cable service and other services.

I. Collection 

What kind of information does this notice cover?  
The Cable Act applies to personally identifiable information that subscribers have furnished to Comcast, or that Comcast has collected using the cable system, in connection with the provision of cable service or other services. The Communications Act applies to CPNI related to our regulated phone and retail Internet services, and certain orders of the Federal Communications Commission apply the CPNI rules to our interconnected voice over Internet protocol communications services.

 **Special Note:** This notice only applies to Comcast Business Internet, phone, TV, and Ethernet Services.  It applies to you as a subscriber to one or more of these services as provided for by applicable law and except as otherwise noted.  It does not cover information that may be collected through any other products, services, or websites, even if you access them through our cable services and even if they are co-branded with Comcast brands or the brands or logos of our affiliated companies. You should read the privacy policies for these other products, services, and websites to learn how they handle your personal information.  You can read the privacy policy for the Comcast Business Services website at http://business.comcast.com/privacy-statement.   

For what purposes may Comcast collect personally identifiable information and CPNI?

The Cable Act authorizes Comcast as a cable operator to use the cable system to collect personally identifiable information concerning any subscriber for the following purposes:

  * to obtain information necessary to render our cable service or other services to our subscribers; and 
  * to detect unauthorized reception of cable communications. 

The Cable Act prohibits us from using the cable system to collect personally identifiable information concerning any subscriber for any purposes other than those listed above without the subscriber’s prior written or electronic consent.  
The Communications Act authorizes us to use, disclose, or permit access to individually identifiable CPNI in our provision of:

  * the telecommunications services from which this information is derived; or 
  * services necessary to, or used in, the provision of these services, including the publishing of directories. 

The Communications Act prohibits us from using CPNI for any purposes other than those listed above except as permitted or required by law or with your approval and as specified in this notice.

What kind of personally identifiable information and CPNI does Comcast collect?  
Comcast collects information from subscribers at several different points when they request, turn on, and use our services under an account we create for them.  Some of this information is personally identifiable information, but much of it is not.  We collect certain personally identifiable information that our subscribers furnish to us in connection with the provision of cable service or other services.  In order to provide reliable, high quality service to subscribers, we keep regular business records containing information about them that may constitute personally identifiable information.  These account records include some of the following information:

  * subscriber name; 
  * service address; 
  * billing address; 
  * e-mail address; 
  * telephone number; 
  * driver’s license number; 
  * social security or tax identification number; 
  * bank account number; and
  * credit card number. 

With respect to phone services, examples of CPNI include information typically available from telephone-related details on your monthly bill:

  * location of service; 
  * technical configuration of service; 
  * type of service; 
  * quantity of service; 
  * amount of use of service; and 
  * calling patterns. 

CPNI does not include a subscriber’s name, address, and telephone number because the Communications Act classifies that information as “subscriber list information” which is not subject to the CPNI protections. However, that information is also subject to certain protections as described below under “To whom may Comcast disclose personally identifiable information?”  The FCC does not have specific rules or definitions regarding CPNI as it relates to Internet access services.  

We also collect and maintain certain other information about a subscriber’s account.  For example, this information may include:

  * your account number;
  * billing, payment, and deposit history; 
  * additional service information; 
  * customer correspondence and communications records; 
  * maintenance and complaint information; 
  * the device identifiers and network addresses of equipment used with your account;
  * records indicating the number of television sets, set-top boxes, modems, telephones, routers, or other devices connected to our cable system; and 
  * additional information about the service options you have chosen. 

Some of our services permit you to establish secondary accounts, and if you do so we collect similar information in order to establish and service the secondary accounts.  During the initial provisioning of our services, and during any subsequent changes or updates to our services, Comcast may collect technical information about your televisions, any set-top boxes, computer hardware and software, cable modems, telephones, other cable or service-related devices, routers, and customization settings and preferences.  Additionally, if you rent your premises, we may have a record of whether landlord permission was required prior to installing our cable services as well as your landlord's name and address.

II. Use How does Comcast use personally identifiable information and CPNI?

We collect, maintain, and use personally identifiable information and CPNI as permitted by the Cable Act and the Communications Act and other applicable laws.  We use this information primarily to conduct business activities related to providing subscribers with our cable service and other services, and to help us detect theft of service.  Generally speaking, we use personally identifiable information in connection with:

  * billing and invoicing; 
  * administration; 
  * surveys; 
  * collection of fees and charges; 
  * marketing; 
  * service delivery and customization; 
  * maintenance and operations; 
  * technical support; 
  * hardware and software upgrades; and 
  * fraud prevention. 

More specifically, we also use personally identifiable information to:

  * install, configure, operate, provide, support, and maintain our cable service and other services; 
  * confirm subscribers are receiving the level(s) of service requested and are properly billed; 
  * identify you when changes are made to your account or services; 
  * make you aware of new content, products, or services that may be of interest to you; 
  * understand the use of, and identify improvements to, our services; 
  * detect unauthorized reception, use, or abuse of our services; 
  * determine any violations of any applicable policies and terms of service; 
  * manage the network supporting our services; 
  * configure and update cable service and other service-related devices and software; and 
  * comply with law. 

The Communications Act further permits Comcast to use, disclose, and permit access to CPNI obtained from our customers, either directly or indirectly, to:

  * initiate, render, bill, and collect for service; 
  * protect our rights and property, and protect our users of these services and other carriers from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful use of, or subscription to, these services; 
  * provide any inbound telemarketing, referral, or administrative services to you for the call’s duration, if you initiated the call and you approve of the use of this information to provide these services; and 
  * provide call location information concerning the user of a voice service during certain emergencies affecting the user. 

Comcast may not use CPNI to market products and services to you other than enhancements to services you already have without your approval in accordance with our policies described below.  Any approval, or denial of approval, for the use of CPNI to market these products and services to you is valid until you affirmatively revoke or limit your approval or denial.  
Comcast transmits, and may collect and store for a period of time, personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information about subscribers when they use our high-speed Internet and phone services to:

  * send and receive e-mail, video mail, and instant messages; 
  * transfer and share files; 
  * make files accessible; 
  * visit websites; 
  * place or receive calls; 
  * leave and receive voice mail messages; 
  * use an applicable communications center or voice center; 
  * establish custom settings or preferences; 
  * communicate with us for support; or 
  * otherwise use the services and their features. 

Our transmission, collection, and storage of this information are necessary to render the services.  In certain situations, third-party service providers may transmit, collect, and store this information on our behalf to provide features of our services.  These third parties are not permitted to use your personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these features.

III. Disclosure 

Under what circumstances may Comcast disclose personally identifiable information to others?   
Comcast considers the personally identifiable information contained in our business records to be confidential.  The Cable Act authorizes Comcast as a cable operator to disclose personally identifiable information concerning any subscriber if the disclosure is:

  * necessary to render, or conduct a legitimate business activity related to, the cable service or other services provided to the subscriber; 
  * required by law or legal process (described below under “When is Comcast required by law to disclose personally identifiable information and CPNI by law?”); or 
  * names and addresses of subscribers for “mailing list” or other purposes (subject to each subscriber’s right to prohibit or limit this disclosure and the CPNI Policy described below under “How do I place myself on Comcast’s ‘do not call’ and ‘do not mail’ lists?”). 

The Cable Act prohibits us as a cable operator from disclosing personally identifiable information concerning any subscriber for any purposes other than those listed above without the subscriber’s prior written or electronic consent.

To whom may Comcast disclose personally identifiable information?  
We may disclose personally identifiable information as provided for in the Cable Act when it is necessary to render, or conduct a legitimate business activity related to, the cable service or other services we provide to you.  We may also collect, use, and disclose information about subscribers in de-identified, anonymous, or aggregate formats, such as ratings surveys and service usage and other statistical reports, which do not personally identify you, your particular viewing habits, or the nature of any transaction you have made over the cable system.    
The frequency of any disclosure of personally identifiable information varies in accordance with our business needs and activities.

The Cable Act authorizes Comcast as a cable operator to disclose limited personally identifiable information to others, such as charities, marketing organizations, or other businesses, for cable or non-cable “mailing list” or other purposes.  From time to time we may disclose your name and address for these purposes.  However, you have the right to prohibit or limit this kind of disclosure by contacting us by telephone at 1-800-391-3000 or by sending us a written request as described below under “How do I contact Comcast?”  Any “mailing list” and related disclosures that we may make are limited by the Cable Act to disclosures of subscriber names and addresses where the disclosures do not reveal, directly or indirectly, (i) the extent of any viewing or other use by the subscriber of a cable service or other service provided by us; or (ii) the nature of any transaction made by the subscriber over our cable system.

We may sometimes disclose personally identifiable information about subscribers to our affiliates or to others who work for us.  We may also disclose personally identifiable information about subscribers to outside auditors, professional advisors, service providers and vendors, potential business merger, acquisition, or sale partners, and regulators.  We make these disclosures as provided for in the Cable Act.  Typically, we make these disclosures when the disclosure is necessary to render, or conduct a legitimate business activity related to, the cable service or other services we provide to you.  We may be required by law or legal process to disclose certain personally identifiable information about subscribers to lawyers and parties in connection with litigation and to law enforcement personnel.

If we (or our parent company) enter into a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, subscribers’ personally identifiable information will, in most instances, be an item transferred in the transaction.  If this notice will be changed as a result of a transaction like that, you should refer below under “Will Comcast notify me if it changes this notice?”

We may also use or disclose personally identifiable information about subscribers without your consent to protect our customers, employees, or property, in emergency situations, to enforce our rights under our terms of service and policies, in court or elsewhere, and as otherwise permitted by law.

When may Comcast disclose personal information to others in connection with phone service?  
Comcast may disclose to others personally identifiable information in connection with features and services such as Caller ID, 911/E911, and directory services as follows:

  * We may transmit your name and/or telephone number to be displayed on a Caller ID device unless you have elected to block such information.  Please note that Caller ID blocking may not prevent the display of your name and/or telephone number when you dial certain business or emergency numbers, 911, 900 numbers, or toll-free 800, 888, 877, 866 or 855 numbers. 
  * We may provide your name, address, and telephone number to public safety authorities and their vendors for inclusion in E911 databases and records, inclusion in “reverse 911” systems, or to troubleshoot 911/E911 record errors. 
  * We may publish and distribute, or cause to be published and distributed, telephone directories in print, on the Internet, and on disks.  Those telephone directories may include subscriber names, addresses, and telephone numbers, without restriction to their use. 
  * We may also make subscriber names, addresses, and telephone numbers available, or cause such subscriber information to be made available, through directory assistance operators. 
  * We may provide subscribers’ names, addresses, and telephone numbers to unaffiliated directory publishers and directory assistance providers for their use in creating directories and offering directory assistance services. 
  * Once our subscribers’ names, addresses, and telephone numbers appear in telephone directories or directory assistance, they may be sorted, packaged, repackaged and made available again in different formats by anyone. 

We take reasonable precautions to ensure that non-published and unlisted numbers are not included in our telephone directories or directory assistance services, but we cannot guarantee that errors will never occur.

When is Comcast required to disclose personally identifiable information and CPNI by law?  
We make every reasonable effort to protect subscriber privacy as described in this notice.  Nevertheless, we may be required by law to disclose personally identifiable information or individually identifiable CPNI about a subscriber.  These disclosures may be made with or without the subscriber’s consent, and with or without notice, in compliance with the terms of valid legal process such as a subpoena, court order, or search warrant.

For subscribers to our TV service, Comcast may be required as a cable operator to disclose personally identifiable information to a third-party or governmental entity in response to a court order.  If the court order is sought by a non-governmental entity, we are required under the Cable Act to notify the subscriber of the court order.  If the court order is sought by a governmental entity, the Cable Act requires that the cable subscriber be afforded the opportunity to appear and contest in a court proceeding relevant to the court order any claims made in support of the court order.  At the proceeding, the Cable Act requires the governmental entity to offer clear and convincing evidence that the subject of the information is reasonably suspected of engaging in criminal activity and that the information sought would be material evidence.

For subscribers to our Internet, phone, and Ethernet services, Comcast may be required to disclose personally identifiable information and individually identifiable CPNI to a private third party in response to a court order, and, if so, we are required to notify the subscriber of the court order.  Comcast may also be required to disclose personally identifiable information and individually identifiable CPNI about subscribers to Internet, phone, and Ethernet services to a government entity in response to a subpoena, court order, or search warrant, for example.  We are usually prohibited from notifying the subscriber of any disclosure of personally identifiable information to a government entity by the terms of the subpoena, court order, or search warrant.

How does Comcast protect personally identifiable information?  
We follow industry-standard practices to take such actions as are necessary to prevent unauthorized access to personally identifiable information by a person other than the subscriber or us.  However, we cannot guarantee that these practices will prevent every unauthorized attempt to access, use, or disclose personally identifiable information.

For how long does Comcast maintain personally identifiable information?  
Comcast maintains personally identifiable information about you in our regular business records while you are a subscriber to our cable service or other services.  We also maintain this information for a period of time after you are no longer a subscriber if the information is necessary for the purposes for which it was collected or to satisfy legal requirements.  These purposes typically include business, legal, or tax purposes.  If these purposes no longer apply, we will destroy, de-identify, or anonymize the information according to our internal policies and procedures.

IV. Customer Access and Choice   
  
How can I see my personally identifiable information or CPNI and correct it, if necessary?

Subscribers may examine and correct, if necessary, their personally identifiable information that is collected and maintained by Comcast in our regular business records.  In most cases, the personally identifiable information contained in these records consists solely of billing and account information.  We will correct our records if you make a reasonable showing that any personally identifiable information we have collected about you is inaccurate.

If you have Internet access, you can view and change certain information yourself by going to www.business.comcast.com/myaccount and signing in with your Comcast username and password.

You may also examine the records containing your personally identifiable information at your local Comcast Business office upon reasonable prior notice to us and during our regular business hours.  If you wish to examine these records, please contact us by mail or telephone at 1-800-391-3000, giving us a reasonable period of time to locate and, if necessary, prepare the information for review, and to arrange an appointment.  You will only be permitted to examine records that contain personally identifiable information about your account and no other account.

If you make an affirmative, written request for a copy of your CPNI, we will disclose the relevant information we have to you at your account address of record, or to any person authorized by you, if we reasonably believe the request is valid.  However, subscribers to our phone services should be aware that we generally do not provide them with records of any inbound or outbound calls or other records that aren’t furnished in the ordinary course of business or which are available only from our archives, without valid legal process.  In addition, we cannot correct any errors in customer names, addresses, or telephone numbers appearing in, or omitted from, our or our vendors’ directory lists until the next available publication of those directory lists.  Further, we may have no control over information appearing in the directory lists or directory assistance services that are not owned by our subsidiaries or us.  Comcast reserves the right to charge you for the reasonable cost of retrieving and photocopying any documents that you request.

How do I give or withhold my approval for Comcast to use CPNI to market additional products and services to me?

Various direct and indirect subsidiaries or affiliates of Comcast Cable Communications, LLC offer many communications-related and non-communications related services.  From time to time we may like to use the CPNI information we have on file to provide you with information about our communications-related products and services or special promotions.  Our use of CPNI may also enhance our ability to offer products and services tailored to your specific needs. In addition, Comcast also offers various other services that are not related to the services to which you subscribe.  Under the CPNI rules, some of those services, such as Comcast TV services, are considered to be non-communications related products and services. Therefore, you may be asked during a telephone call with one of our representatives for your oral consent to Comcast’s use of your CPNI for the purpose of providing you with an offer for communications related or non-communications related products and services.  If you provide your oral consent for Comcast to do so, Comcast may use your CPNI only for the duration of that telephone call in order to offer you additional services.  If you deny or restrict your approval for us to use your CPNI, you will suffer no effect on how we provide any services to which you subscribe.   

How do I place myself on Comcast’s “do not call” and “do not mail” lists?

You may ask us to put your name on our internal company “do not call” and “do not mail” lists so that you do not receive marketing or promotional telephone calls or postal mail from us or made at our request by completing the information in the Marketing Opt-Out Manager, available at: <http://businesshelp.comcast.com/help-and-support/accounts-billing/do-not-call-do-not-mail-registry-requests/>.  You also have the right to prohibit or limit disclosure of your personally identifiable information for “mailing list” or other purposes as described above in this notice by completing the information in the Marketing Opt-Out Manager.  

If you prefer to contact Comcast in writing instead of by telephone, you may send a written request to the address listed below under “How do I contact Comcast?”  Be sure to include your name and address, your Comcast Business account number, and a daytime telephone number where you can be reached if we have any questions about your request.  The person who is identified in our billing records as the authorized representative of the subscriber should sign the written request.  If you have a joint account, a request by one party will apply to the entire account.  If you have multiple accounts, your notice must separately identify each account covered by the request.

What e-mail communications will Comcast send to subscribers and how do I manage them?  
We may send a welcome e-mail and sometimes other information to new subscribers to our cable service and other services.  We may also send service-related announcements to our subscribers from time to time.  You may not opt-out of these service-related communications.  If you fail to check your primary e-mail address for service-related announcements, you may miss important information about our services.

We reserve the right to send you promotional or commercial e-mail as permitted by applicable law.  You can manage the promotional or commercial e-mails Comcast may send to you by logging in on the Web page located at www.business.comcast.com/myaccount and following the directions there. We may ask for additional information on this preferences page.  By providing this additional information to us we will be able to better inform you of special offers and promotions in your area.  If you no longer wish to receive these e-mails you may opt-out of receiving them by going to the same page and changing your contact preferences.

What can I do if I think my privacy rights have been violated?  
If you believe that you have been aggrieved by any act of ours in violation of the Cable Act or other applicable laws, we encourage you to contact us directly as described below in “How do I contact Comcast?” in order to resolve your question or concern.  You may also enforce the limitations imposed on us by the Cable Act as applicable with respect to your personally identifiable information through a civil lawsuit seeking damages, attorneys' fees, and litigation costs.  Other rights and remedies may be available to you under federal or other applicable laws as well.  This customer privacy notice neither supersedes nor modifies any arbitration agreement to which you may be bound relating to the provision of our TV service, Internet service, phone, and Ethernet to you as a subscriber to services.

Will Comcast notify me if it changes this notice?  
As required by the Cable Act, we will provide you with a copy of this customer privacy notice at the time we enter into an agreement to provide any cable service or other service to you, and annually afterwards, or as otherwise permitted by law.  You can view the most current version of this notice by going to http://business.comcast.com/customer-notifications/customer-privacy-statement.

We may modify this notice at any time.  We will notify you of any material changes through written, electronic, or other means and as otherwise permitted by law.  If you find the changes to this notice unacceptable, you have the right to cancel your service.  If you continue to use the service following notice of the changes, we will deem that to be your acceptance of and consent to any revisions to the privacy notice.  This includes your consent for any personally identifiable information that we may collect and use starting on the revised notice’s effective date, as well as for any personally identifiable information that we have collected prior to the revised notice’s effective date.

How do I contact Comcast?  
If you have any questions or suggestions regarding this privacy notice, or wish to contact us about your personal information, please reach us as follows:  
Phone:  1-800-391-3000  

Website: http://business.comcast.com/contact  

Mail:  Comcast Cable Communications, LLC  
Attn: Comcast Business - Customer Privacy Notice  
One Comcast Center  
Philadelphia, PA 19103-2838

Revised and effective:  May 10, 2017
